HALEEM BELLO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

P (470) 549-2477

E thehaleembello@gmail.com

A Atlanta, GA, USA

W http://genialtechie.xvz

I am a Full-Stack JavaScript Developer specializing in front-end frameworks such as react and next.js. I frequently work with React, Node.js, data structures and algorithms, blockchain, and serverless technologies like AWS and Netlify Functions. To hone my skills, I concentrate on building beautiful, user-friendly applications for local businesses and fostering a creative firm called loudronline.

KEY SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, Web3.js, Next.js, APIs, Git, MongoDB, Graphql, Decentralized Apps, Blockchain.

EDUCATION

01/2021 - PRESENT (PART-TIME)

Georgia Gwinnett College | B.Sc. in Software Development

GPA: 3.3/4

Learning asynchronous, and remote teamwork, and meeting deadlines

12/2016 - 08/2020

University Of Lagos, Nigeria | B.Sc. in Electrical & Electronics Engineering

GPA: 2.2/5

EXPERIENCE

11/2022 - 12/2022

Freelance Developer | JA Inflatables

- Overhauled obsolete legacy code and implemented Nextjs across application resulting in increased usability and reduced load time
- Used the Square-API to implement an e-commerce platform that assisted in increasing online revenue to 60% of total revenue.
- Designed and integrated inventory tracking and reservation management systems with the company's new ecommerce platform.
- Improved Search Engine Optimization by using server-side rendering and conducting a full audit.

01/2021 - PRESENT

Partner & Lead Developer | loudronline

- Co-founded and manage a creative firm that assists emerging creators via social media communities, a blog, and an online shop.
- To improve SEO and overall webpage performance, I migrated the firm's frontend stack from WordPress to
- Developed and integrated an online shop to showcase emerging creators' work and generate revenue through merchandise sales.

06/2018 - 08/2018

Web Developer Intern | Zikoko Online Magazine

- Used HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to assist the development team in the design and implementation of website updates and new features.
- Collaborated with the editorial team to create and maintain website content, which included writing and formatting articles.
- Assisted in the testing and debugging of web applications and identified and resolved technical issues.

06/2017 - 09/2017

Web Developer Intern | Enplan Group

- Used HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to assist the marketing team in the design and development of the company website.
- I utilized Adobe Creative Cloud to design graphics and visual elements for use on the website and in marketing materials, including brochures and email campaigns.
- Collaborated with the engineering team to collect and organize website content, such as project case studies and technical documents.